## Curriculum Vitae

Contact Details

Mobile: 079 1416 6027

Email: <u>heatherlsuen@gmail.com</u>

Address: 72 Mildenhall Crescent, Notts, NG5 5RS

# **Heather Suen**

## **Personal Statement**

I am an inquisitive and creative problem solver, pragmatic and versatile in my approach. I am passionate about learning and applying new tools and techniques to keep my skills fresh. I am motivated by helping people achieve their goals and am a natural advocate for user experience. I work best in a team who are also supportive and collaborate effectively. I enjoy the variance of challenges presented by the analyst role, the space of autonomy and the opportunity to succeed as a team.

My Myers Briggs personality type is consistently ISTJ-A, aka the logistician.

### **Career History**

## **RightIndem**

## Product Owner & Business Analyst, January 2017 - Present

Broadening my Business Analyst skills and leadership experience to include the role of Product Owner, at RightIndem I empower multiple teams to build and deliver quality products.

Adopting agile methodology, I articulate and communicate the intent of the overarching epic of work and I am responsible for writing, refining and prioritising backlogs of user stories. I embellish stories with supporting artefacts such as data maps, user journey mapping, ubiquitous language, process flows, test-driven development in gherkin format, behaviour driven development, technical requirements and acceptance criteria.

As a Product Owner I support the delivery teams on a daily basis by removing blockers, impediments and I manage risk, dependencies and issues with the wider business. Working closely with internal and external stakeholders I determine minimum viable product to ensure the squads continuously release value to the end user of the software we build.

#### Capital One

## Identity and Access Management Consultant, July 2016 – January 2017

I joined the IAM team to establish a new service offering, and help the team enhance existing processes via agile iterative development. By utilising my skills as a BSA, I successfully embedded compliance frameworks into operational processes whilst championing excellent customer experience. Introducing the team to scrum and Kanban delivery methodology has empowered the team to revisit their approach to improvement whilst maintaining delivery momentum.

In my role I have supported the annual disaster recovery exercise, incident resolution and updates from US initiatives. Incorporating US intent to the nuances of UK functionality has allowed me to develop strong key relationships with my counterparts in the US to leverage expertise to benefit our understanding and effectiveness.

#### Business Systems Analyst, March 2014 – July 2016

From my role as resource coordinator, I took the opportunity to learn new skills and apply my business knowledge to the BSA role and project delivery. As a BSA, I delivered a variety of projects, using both waterfall and agile methodology. I have been involved in updating legacy infrastructure, enhancing system functionality, improving end user experience and demonstrating compliance.

Stakeholder management is key to this role, which has enabled me to utilise my client relationship skills to effectively communicate across the business, influence decision makers and also engage external organisations via a wide range of mediums such as workshops, presentations, demonstrations and written corporate documentation.

I have developed many analytical techniques and applied my knowledge of IT systems and processes to expand and define potential solutions when exploring the needs of the business. Throughout delivery of projects I ensure the solution meets the intent, delivers value to the customer and is implemented in accordance with budget, resource and deadline constraints.

#### IT Resource Coordinator, March 2012 - March 2014

Changing industries from legal to financial and fulfilling a role in the IT division of an organisation, rather than in marketing, has allowed me to further develop my administrative and team work skills by supporting a larger team directly.

My primary role was to work with the various project delivery teams to ensure that tasks are appropriately resourced; this involves:-

- Recording all the resource requests for the Infrastructure Delivery and Architect teams.
- Maintaining accurate and up to date records of allocated time and availability (project allocations, annual leave, training, etc.).
- Providing an effective communication channel within the team and with the wider business as a whole.

In addition to the time management and communication responsibilities above, I also supported the team by:-

- Facilitating meetings and taking minutes
- Collating data and running reports
- Event management and support
- Organising internal team building events
- Process development and document formatting
- Delivering training and troubleshooting

I worked closely with my line manager and the management team, re-prioritising work quickly when required and completing urgent tasks to tight deadlines.

## **Geldards LLP**

### Business Development Assistant, August 2011 – March 2012

To develop my career I moved to Geldards LLP, a larger, more commercially focused law firm. My main role in the Marketing Team was orientated around replying to tenders (in Public, Government and Private sectors) and managing the bid process from initially registering interest with the contracting body through to compiling the tender response and supporting the legal team with their final presentation.

Whilst my role had a strong bias towards business development, targeting and client relationship management, I also supported the team in a marketing capacity with regards to events, internal and external communications (to clients, stakeholders, industry peers, etc.) advertising and public relations. My broad responsibilities at Fraser Brown (listed below) have given me experience in a range of marketing disciplines tailored and specifically utilised in the legal industry.

#### **Fraser Brown Solicitors**

#### Business Development Assistant, July 2006 – August 2011

#### Roles & Responsibilities:-

- Implement marketing plans and campaigns
- Event organisation including fundraisers, seminars, exhibitions and professional networking events
- Profile building and raising awareness through public relations
- General advertising in local and trade publications
- Compiling data and reporting marketing campaign performance and results to the Management Board
- Coordinating calendars, organising and chairing meetings
- Training and supporting staff informally on a one to one basis to help with all aspects of Business Development and CRM
- Editing and compiling the monthly internal newsletter

#### Skills:-

- Time management and organisational skills
- Proficient user of Microsoft Office software including Excel, PowerPoint and Outlook
- Exceptional communication skills, both in written format and verbally
- Networking and building professional relationships
- Skilful administrator
- Able to prioritise tasks and manage a heavy workload
- Experienced team worker and motivator
- Able to remain calm under pressure and meet challenging deadlines

#### **Broadway Cinema**

Usher, August 2004 - December 2012

Working at Broadway as an usher has taught me how to work solo with large groups of the public whilst supporting other members of staff simultaneously. I have developed excellent customer service skills and am responsive to the needs of the customers. I am quick to manage situations and pro-actively ensure the comfort and safety of Broadway customers.

#### **Professional Training**

Foundation in Business Analysis; Assist KD, October 2015

ITIL Foundation for Service Management; Purple Griffin, February 2013

Chartered Institute of Marketing (CIM) Introductory Certificate in Marketing; New College Nottingham, September 2009

NVQ Level 3 in Business Administration (Advanced Apprenticeship); Intec Business College Nottingham, November 2007

Computer Keyboard Skills (Touch Typing) Certificate; Pitman Training Centre Nottingham, September 2007

### Education

As-Levels in Chemistry, Critical Thinking, English Literature, Mathematics and Textiles: New College Nottingham, 2004 – 2006

GCSE's in Art, English Language, English Literature, French, Geography, Information & Computer Technology, Mathematics, Science and Textiles; Harry Carlton Secondary School, 2001 – 2004